Duane Family Collection 1764-1933 Mss.SMs.Coll.2
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 1764-1933; 1.5 lin. feet
  - ALS to William John Duane, 1842 March 22; 3 pgs.; Conway, F. W
    Comments on Duane's journal.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1842 September 20; 1 pg.; Neal, Joseph Clay, 1807-1847
    Note (thanks) accompanying return of one of Duane's books.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1844 July 6; 1 pg.; Walker, Robert John
    Thanks Duane for use of map. Concerning the Louisiana purchase and Texas.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1845 January 24; 1 pg.; Minor, Benjamin Blake, 1818-1905
    States difficulty of obtaining book Duane desires. Refers to Edgar Allen Poe.
  - ALS to C. W. Laurence, 1845 July 30; 1 pg.; Tilden, Samuel J., (Samuel Jones), 1814-1886
    Letter of reccomendation for a John Towsend for a position in Customs Department.
  - AQS, a fair copy, to Rev. Charles Hodge, 1845 Nov. 3; 2 pgs.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Existence and Location of Copies note
    FILM 54-65 FRAME 176.
    Typescript presented by Whitfield J. Bell, from original in possession of Miss S.M. Hodge, Oct. 1957.
    Concerns the papers of Benjamin Franklin and the Bache family.
  - ALS to William John Duane, 1846 June 23; 3 pgs.; Chaloner, John, 1780-1862
    News of Duane's son (Richard Bache Duane) visit to Clommel (Ireland). Political and social climate in Ireland.
  - ALS to William John Duane, 1848 July 14; 1 pg.; Dallas, George Mifflin, 1792-1864
    Promises aid in helping Duane, will see President (Tyler) regarding same.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1849 August 9; 1 pg.; Duane, Sarah
    Old call number B:D852.2. 1977 32ms (40).
  - Will and testement, [1850]; 2 pgs.; Duane, Sarah
    Desires that only male relatives and male close friends attend her funeral.
    Old call number B:D852.2. 1977 32ms.
  - Thoughts on religion, [1850]; 1 pg.; Duane, Sarah
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1851 March 31; 1 pg.; Mayer, Brantz, 1809-1879
    Requests a copy of an address given by Duane before the Historical Society of Pennsylvania.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1852 January 12; 2 pgs.; Bancroft, George, 1800-1891
    Acknowledgement and thanks for a copy of a Franklin letter. Mentions Duane's interest in Pennsylvania history.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1852 February 19; 3 pgs.; Schoolcraft, Henry Rowe, 1793-1864
    Acknowledges receipt of copy of Historical Society publication. Mentions Duane's interest in Congressional action regarding Native Americans.
  - Deed: Philadelphia property belonging to William Duane (1807-1882), 1853 June 9; 1 pg.; McCrees, John
    Old call number B:D852. Oversize.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1856 January 5; 1 pg.; Bancroft, George, 1800-1891
    Acknowledges debt to Society?
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1856 January 5; 1 pg.; Cogswell, Joseph Green, 1786-1871
    Note accompanying and acknowledging payment of subscription to the Seventy Six Society.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1856 January 30; 2 pgs.; Wetmore, Prosper Montgomery, 1798-1876
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1856 April 16; 6 pgs.; Sparks, Jared, 1789-1866
    Encloses copies of two letters from John Dickinson to Arthur Lee--1774 August 20, and 22nd. Concerning Arthur Lee and Silas Deane. For encs., see: John Dickinson to A.Lee; Aug. 20, 1774, and Oct. 27, 1774.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1856 October 2; 1 pg.; Curtis, George William, 1824-1892
    News of "friend Balch's" ill health.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1858 March 30; 4 pgs.; Parton, James, 1822-1891
    Thanks Duane for editing his work. Concerning a book on Franklin and some supposed "unpleasantness" to his "grandfather [R.Bache?]." Refers to Andrew Jackson.
  - ALS to John Sartain?, 1858 July 2; 1 pg.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Asks for picture to be delivered. [Possibly the B.Franklin picture which belonged to C. W. Bache.]
  - Receipt to the Academy of Fine Arts for portrait of Benjamin Franklin, 1858 July 6; 1 pg.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Duane signs receipt on behalf of Catherine W. Bache.
  - Toasts...Delegates to the Quarantine and Sanitary Convention, 1859 April 29; 1 pg.; Common Council of New York
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1859 September 29; 4 pgs.; Strong, George Augustus, 1832-1912
    Details items left behind to be disposed of.
  - Commentary on his sisters, [1850's]; 4 pgs.; Duane, William, 1808-1882
    Fond recollections of sisters (now disceased). Contains instructions to forward a collection of family correspondence (not enclosed) to his grandson, Russell. Also contains a table of contents of correspondence (with no letters).
  - Menu for Banquet: Fourth National Quarantine and Sanitary Convention, 1860 June 16; 2 pgs.; City Council of Boston
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1860 December 27; 3 pgs.; Parton, James, 1822-1891
    Responds to letter received on the 24th. Mentions beginning work on Benjamin Franklin.
  - ALS to George Morgan?, 1861 February 25, March 1, 4; 4 pgs.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Responds to letter of 26th of prior month. Recalls his trip to Clonnel, Ireland in his youth. Mentions national political crisis (impending civil war), "At the very moment at which I am writing, I may say, the crisis is about to be breached."
  - Receipt: gift of Deborah Duane, 1861 April 24; 1 pg. Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Edward Everett and Edward Capen.; Boston Public Library
    Donated Franklin correspondence circa era 1779.
    Old call number B:D852. Printed material.
  - ALS to Birgadier General Prentiss, 1861 October 4; 1 pg.; Frémont, John Charles, 1813-1890
    Received dispatches, requests information as to continuing situation.
  - ALS to Charles Williams Duane, 1861 November 25; 1 pg.; Potter, Alonzo, 1800-1865
    Regrets. Will not be able to meet at time agreed on.
  - ALS to F. A. Packard, 1863 February 10; 1 pg.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Regrets late acknowledgement of letter. Mentions suffering from the "most bitter affliction of my life," his wife's impending death.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1863 December 6; 4 pgs.; Brewster, Anne Maria Hampton, 1819-1892
    Acknowledgement of editing of first portion of book.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1863 December 25; 1 pg.; Holland, Josiah Gilbert, 1819-1881
    Thanks for editing book.
  - ALS to William John Duane, 1864 February 18; 4 pgs.; Parton, James, 1822-1891
    Concerns a book on Franklin. Needs a picture of Deborah Franklin.
    Old catalog number B:D852.
  - ALS to Charles Williams Duane, 1864 April 4; 1 pg.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Sends his wife's silverware to grandson, along with a copies of the works of Benjamin Franklin originally given to William John's mother.
  - ALS to "Dear Father", 1864 November 28; 2 pgs.; Macer, Anna
    Asks for consent of marriage.
  - Inventory of estate of William John Duane, 1865 October 7; 6 pgs. D.S.[on original]:Charles H. Kingston and William E. Littleton.; Kingston, Charles and William E. Littleton
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1865 December 25; 1 pg.; Holland, Josiah Gilbert, 1819-1881
    Thanks for agreeing to edit book.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1870 May 2, Sept. 1; 4 pgs.; Moore, George Washington, 1814-1899
    Concerns editorial matters for article in American Monthly Magazine.
  - Stock certificate, Mercantile Library Company of Philadelphia, 1870 May 13; 1 pg.; Library Company of Philadelphia.
    $10.00 share.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1870 November 7; 2 pgs.; Moore, George Washington, 1814-1899
    Acknowledges receipt of the Commissioners of Fairmont Park report.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1871 March 27; 4 pgs.; Lossing, Benson John, 1813-1891
    Clarifies genealogy of mutual acquaintances. Mentions that the son of one of their friends was killed two years ago with the 7th cavalry. Mentions work on life of Philip Schulyer. Refers to James Madison.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1871 March 31; 4 pgs.; Moore, George Washington, 1814-1899
    Invitation to visit home in London. Mentions receipt of Philadelphia Park Report (1871).
  - ALS to Simon Cameron, 1872 January 30; 2 pgs.; Elliott, William, 1851-1934
    Comments on recent election and Republican politics In Pennsylvania and Philadelphia.
  - ALS to Charles Williams Duane, 1873 March 11; 2 pgs.; Odenheimer, William Henry, 1817-1879
    Confirms cannon transfer to new diocese in New Jersey. Welcomes Duane back to area.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1873 December 4; 3 pgs.; Moore, George Washington, 1814-1899
    Thanks for sending pamphlet on names.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1874 July 7; 3 pgs.; Moore, George Washington, 1814-1899
    Sends address, review of a book. Requests a copy of Duane's latest book.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1875 February 10; 6 pgs.; Moore, George Washington, 1814-1899
    Queries into Duane's knowledge of various known personages in New York and Philadelphia. Mentions desire to travel to Philadelphia next year. Encloses copy of a letter from him to a Theodore Ledyard Cuyler 1875 February 10.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1875 December 15; 3 pgs.; U. S. Treasury Department
    Report of a requested audit of Col. William Duane (his grandfather, editor of the Aurora), dept. of the Army. Mentions $2,397.22 due Duane senior, paid out on may 17, 1824.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1877 February 20; 4 pgs.; Moore, George Washington, 1814-1899
    Acknowledgement and thanks for copy of "Extracts from the diary of Christopher Marshall."
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1880 January 5; 4 pgs.; Bache, Albert Dabadie, 1832-1895
    Family genealogy inquiry, descendents of William Temple Franklin.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1880 December 15; 8 pgs.; Holt, Emily Sarah, b. 1836
    Responds to editorial criticism, rebuts most of Duane's suggestions.
  - ALS to Charles Williams Duane, 1882 October 20; 1 pg.; Scarborough, John, bp., 1831-1914
    Confirms Duane's leaving current post as pastor.
  - ALS to Charles Williams Duane, 1885 July 9; 3 pgs.; Davis, Thomas F
    Directs release of funds and an assistant pastor to aid in "missionary work" by church volunteers in and around Jenkintown.
  - ALS to Charles Williams Duane, 1886 March 6; 2 pgs.; Stevens, William Bacon, 1815-1887
    Responds to query from Duane. States that it is a mistake for candidates for the ministry to marry, as it proves a distraction.
  - ALS to Charles Williams Duane, 1886 May 10; 1 pg.; Stevens, William Bacon, 1815-1887
    Notice of obligatory diocese meeting.
  - ALS to Charles Williams Duane, 1886 June 26; 3 pgs.; Huntington, William Reed, 1838-1909
    Acknowledges acquaintance with individual Duane previously asked about. Gives testimonial to character of man in question.
  - ALS to Charles Williams Duane, 1888 March 5; 2 pgs.; Brooks, Phillips, 1835-1893
    Comments on matter concerning Board of Trustees of Massachusetts General Hospital.
  - ALS to Charles Williams Duane, 1888 May 25; 3 pgs.; Whitaker, [Ozi] William
    Disposition of church collections.
  - Will of Maria Hall, 1888 June 19; 5 pgs.; Hall, Maria
  - ALS to Charles Williams Duane, 1889 April 5; 1 pg.; Davies, Thomas Frederick, 1831-1905
    Notification of material sent. Mentions upcoming meeting.
  - Collection of quotes, 1889 November 30; 3 pgs.; Duane, Charles Williams and William John
    Includes explanation of the expression "O.K" Attributed to President Jackson as corruption of the expression "all correct."
  - ALS to Charles Williams Duane, 1890 January 9; 2 pgs.; Burgess, Frederick, Bp., 1853-1925
    Discusses convention and diocese bounderies.
  - Will of Maria Hall; codecil, 1890 June 14; 5 pgs.; Hall, Maria
  - ALS to Charles Williams Duane, 1890 June 21; 3 pgs.; Nichols, William Ford, bp., 1849-
    News of committees and conventions.
  - ALS to Charles Williams Duane, 1891 May 21; 1 pg.; Whitaker, Ozi William
    Church business. Mentions west Philadelphia.
  - ALS to Russell Duane, 1892 May 9; 2 pgs.; Blaine, James Gillespie, 1830-1893
    Appointment as Assistant Counsel for preparation of Case in matter submitted before the Bering Sea Board of Arbitration.
  - ALS to Charles Williams Duane?, 1896 February 2; 16 pgs.; Morris, Roland Sletor, 1874-1945
    Church news.
  - ALS to Charles Williams Duane, 1896 December 19; 1 pg.; Perry, William Stevens, 1832-1898
    Requests images of landmark Philadelphia churches.
  - ALS to Charles Williams Duane, 1896 December 26; 2 pgs.; Strong, George Augustus, 1832-1912
    Encloses check for $10.00 for appreciation of Christmas service. Thanks for answer to query.
  - ALS to Mrs. Thomas B. Morris, [1896]; 3 pgs.; Morris, Roland Sletor, 1874-1945
    Family news. Mentions college life at Princeton University.
  - ALS to Emma Cushman Duane, 1898 November 27; 2 pgs.; Wolcott, Roger, 1847-1900
    Mentions Fair that Emma (Mrs. Charles Williams Duane) Duane is organizing.
  - TLS to Roland S. Morris, 1901 September 23; 1 pg.; Dodge, George M
    Cost estimates for improvements to property.
  - ALS to Charles Williams Duane, 1902 May 11; 2 pgs.; Strong, George Augustus, 1832-1912
    Sends requested address update.
  - TLS to Charles Williams Duane, 1903 January 28; 1 pg.; Lawrence, William
    Sends enclosure. Thanks for advice. Request notice of date Duane will sail.
  - TLS to Charles Williams Duane, 1904 February 12; 1 pg.; Brown, William M
    Request by the bishop of Arkansas for a venue and time in which to deliver a lecture, "The American Negro Problem." States that lecture is open defense of southern position.
  - ALS to Charles Williams Duane, 1904 March 21; 1 pg.; Allen, Alexander Viets Griswold, 1841-1908
    Sends regrets about missing a meeting of "the Club."
  - ALS to Charles Williams Duane, 1904 March 21; 1 pg.; Bowne, Borden Parker, 1847-1910
  - ALS to Charles Williams Duane, 1904 March 22; 2 pgs.; Normandie, James de, 1836-1924
  - ALS to Charles Williams Duane, 1904 March 23; 1 pg.; Hodges, George, 1856-1919
  - ALS to Charles Williams Duane, 1904 March 23; 1 pg.; Huntington, W. E
  - ALS to W. Dawees Roberts, 1904 September 14; 1 pg.; Carmichael, James, 1835-1908
    Informs bishop of Massachusetts that he (as bishop of Montreal) will not be able to stay as long as desired after sermon. Refers to William Laurence.
  - ALS to Charles Williams Duane, 1904 September 27; 1 pg.; Carmichael, James, 1835-1908
    Regrets will not be able to attend meeting.
  - ALS to Charles Williams Duane, 1904 October 20; 1 pg.; Capen, Edward Warren, 1870-
    Clarification of meeting Duane.
  - ALS to Charles Williams Duane, 1907 January 25; 3 pgs.; Merriman, Daniel, 1838-1912
    Sends regrets about missing a meeting of "the Club." Mentions will be spending time in the White Mountains enjoying winter sports.
  - TLS to Charles Williams Duane, 1907 January 28; 1 pg.; Gordon, George Angier, 1853-1929
  - ALS to Charles Williams Duane, 1907 January 29; 2 pgs.; Warren, William Fairfield, 1833-1929
  - TLS to Charles Williams Duane, 1907 January 31; 1 pg.; Hodges, George, 1856-1919
  - TLS to Russell Duane, 1908 December 4; 1 pg.; Gordon, James Gay, 1877-
    Forwards book by William Duane.
  - TLS: Fundraising letters for the election of Woodrow Wilson, 1912 October; 10 pgs.; Morris, Roland Sletor, 1874-1945
    This item, only,presented by Samuel Moyerman, Jan. 19, 1953.
  - TLS to Emma Cushman Duane, 1917 December 24; 1 pg. and enc.of newspaper clipping and translation of writing,and add.; Morris, Roland Sletor, 1874-1945
    Letter of introduction for Japanese muscian, Kosaku Yamada.
  - ALS to Mary Moris Duane, 1918 January 18; 32 pgs.; Morris, Roland Sletor, 1874-1945
    Family news, including his concern over their mother. Also life in Japan and the U.S. embassy.
  - ALS to Mary Morris Duane, 1918 August 21; 12 pgs.; Morris, Roland Sletor, 1874-1945
    Family news, news from Japan. Written on U.S. embassy letterhead. Includes three photos with separate annotations. Mentions the Ingersoll family. Photograph as U.S. ambassador to Japan.
  - A.D. to Mary Morris Duane, 1918 October 17; 1 pg.; Morris, Roland Sletor, 1874-1945
    Old catalog number B:D852.m. Unlocated as of 11/28/07.
  - TLS to Russell Duane, 1921 December 9; 2 pgs.; Rogers, James S
    Forwards a letter from his grandfather (William John Duane) 1840 March 21 to a John Y. Clark.
  - ALS to Mrs. Thomas B. Morris, 1922 August 24; 10 pgs.; Morris, Roland Sletor, 1874-1945
    Family news, news from Japan. Mentions an international conference at which he was formally recognized for his work. Comments on U.S. politics.
  - ALS to Mrs. Thomas B. Morris, 1922 September 14; 4 pgs.; Morris, Roland Sletor, 1874-1945
    Family news. Will see her Monday.
  - ALS to "My Dear Cousin", 1923 June 12; 1 pg; Duane, Stella
    Comments on a letter lent her, originally from Steven Girard.
  - ALS to Mary Morris Duane, 1933 August 31; 11 pgs.; Morris, Roland Sletor, 1874-1945
    Family news. Extremely busy, especially with work for Washington. Describes their "vacation life" and visitors.
  - ALS to William John Duane, 1 pg.; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Addresses Duane as "My dear cousin." Requests a box of manuscripts.
  - Form for conveyance in trust (indenture), 2 pgs.; Binney, Horace, 1780-1875
    Hand drafted, blank spaces left for names and dates.
  - Brooks family genealogical note, n.d.; 1 pg.; Brooks family
    1756 - 1805.
  - ALS to Adeline Martin, n.d.; 5 pgs.; C. S
    Personal.
  - List of marriages performed while Rector of St. Andrew's Church; 1882-1890, 4 pgs; Duane, Charles Williams
  - ALS to "Dear Cousin", n.d. (July 1); 2 pgs.; Duane, Margaret B
    Pertains to the Franklin? Prayer book.
    Old catalog number 264.03 C47.
  - ALS to Captain McHenry?, n.d.; 3 pgs.; Duane, William, 1760-1835
    Memorandums to McHenry.
  - Review of the book, Looking Backward, by Bellamy., n.d.; 36 pgs.; Duane, William, 1808-1882
  - AL to Amos Kendall, 5 pgs.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Proposed instructions (draft) to Kendall as agent of the bank of the United States.
  - ALS to William John Duane, 1 pg.; Garland, J
    Instructions to commence investigation.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), n.d.; 4 pgs.; Hull, [Mrs.] G. S
    Concerns a contest Hull entered as a child in which she & [Edgar Allan] Poe won prizes.
  - Amos Kendall's return of the state banks, 4 pgs.; Kendall, Amos, 1789-1869
    Kendall reports back to William John Duane, as Secretary of the Treasury, the ability of the state banks to handle the transfer of public funds.
  - ALS to Charles Williams Duane, n.d.; 3 pgs.; Laurence, William
    Church business.
  - ALS to Charles Williams Duane, n.d.; 3 pgs.; Laurence, William
  - ALS to Charles Williams Duane, n.d.; 1 pg.; Laurence, William
  - ALS to W. Romeyn Benjamin, n.d.; 5 pgs.; Pringle, Mrs. M. T
    Concerns bookplates.
  - ALS to W. Romeyn Benjamin, n.d.; 3 pgs.; Pringle, Mrs. M. T
    Encloses bookplates and prices for same.
  - ALS to W. Romeyn Benjamin, n.d.; 7 pgs.; Pringle, Mrs. M. T
    Regards purchase of bookplates.
- Series II. Printed Material, 1814-1911; 14 items
  - William Duane (1760-1835): Commission as Lieutenant Colonel in the Pennsylvania militia, 1814 August 25; 1 pg.; Synder, Simon (Governor of Pennsylvania)
    Commissioned as Lieutenant Colonel of the first brigade of the first division, Philadelphia.
    From scrapbook. OS
  - Banknote: twenty five cents (US), 1815 July 4; 1 pg.; Schuykill Bank
    Signed by Nicholas Biddle.
  - Thomas P. McMahon: Commission as Colonel in the Pennsylvania militia, 1821 August 3; 1 pg; Heister, Joseph, 1752-1832
    Commissioned as Colonel of the first brigade of the first division, Philadelphia.
  - Nineteenth annual report of the Dorcas Society of St. Andrews Church, [1850]; 4 pgs.; St. Andrew's Church
    Old call number B:D852.2. 1977 32ms. Printed material.
  - Dinner menu for commerative dinner, 1856 November 8; 2 pgs.; Historical Society of Pennsylvania.
    Menu of dinner sponsored by the Historical Society of Pennsylvania commerating the 174th anniversary of William Penn at Chester.
    Old call number B:D852.3. Printed material.
  - Biographical memoir: William John Duane, 1868; 28 pgs.; Duane, William, 1807-1882
  - Deed and mortage, 1900 May 23; 3 pgs.; Silverman, Simon
    Deed (and mortage) to Samuel L. Danishevsky
    Old call number B:D852.1. Printed material.
  - Receipt for property, mortage to Samuel L. Danishevsky, 1900 May 23; 2 pgs.; Silverman, Simon
  - TDS: Bill of sale and transfer of rights to Charles Williams Duane, 1911 May 17; 2 pgs.; Rouillard, Elmer H. and Rouillard, Irving G
    Deed of properties signed over to Duane for one dollar.
  - TDS: Release to Charles Williams Duane, 1911 May 24; 3 pgs.; Rouillard, Millicent A
    Deed of properties signed over to Duane for one dollar. Signs as Guardian for primary signatories, Elmer and Irving Rouillard.
  - Broadside, n.d.; 2 pgs.; Unidentified
    Concerns Treaty of Amity, commerce and navigation... Peace treaty with Great Brittain.
  - Colonial currency, n.d.; 7 items; Unidentified
    Some items published by Benjamin Franklin.
  - Newspaper clippings, n.d; 2 items; Longfellow and Whittier
    Poems.
    Old call number B:D852.2. Printed items.
  - Ode to Bogle, n.d.; 1 pg.; Unidentified
    Newspaper clipping; poem.
    Old call number B:D852.1. Printed items.
- Series III. Photographs & Prints, 1790 - 1890; 62 items
  - Engraving of Horace Walpole, ca 1790; 1 engraving; Sartain, John, 1808-1897, engraver, from painting by Eckardt
    7" x 5 3/4"
  - Engraving of Charles James Fox, ca 1790; 1 engraving; Unidentified
    4 1/2" x 5 3/4"
  - Engraving: "View of Calcutta from the esplanade", ca 1790; 1 engraving; Unidentified
    6 1/4' x 7 3/4"
  - Engraving of Charles James Fox, ca 1790; 1 engraving; Cook, J. W., engraver, from portrait by Joshua Reynolds
    8" x 6 1/2"
  - Engraving of High Street, with the First Presbyterian Church, ca 1790; 1 engraving; Unidentified
    Philadelphia.
    8 1/2" x 10 1/2"
  - Engraving of Mathew Duane, 1798; 1 engraving; Milon, James, engraver from image by Gyles Hussy
    7 3/4" x 6 1/2"
  - Engraving of William Pitt, ca 1800; 1 engraving; Thomson, James, engraver, from image by J. Hoppner
    8" x 5 3/4"
  - Engraving of [King] George the third, ca 1800; 1 engraving; Unidentified
    6 1/4" x 4"
  - Engraving of Pennsylvania Hospital in 1800, ca 1800; 1 engraving; Unidentified
  - Engraving of Thomas McKean, ca 1800; 1 engraving; Welch, T. B. (Thomas B.), 1814-1874, engraver, from portrait by Gilbert Stuart
    8" x 6"
  - Engraving of Pennsylvania Statehouse, Philadelphia, ca 1800; 1 engraving; Unidentified
    7 1/2" x 10 1/4"
  - Engraving of Simon Snyder, ca 1800; 1 engraving; Pinx, W. Wooley, engraver, from image by Tiebout
    Governor of Pennsylvania.
    10 1/4" x 7"
  - Engraving of Col. William Duane, ca 1820; 1 engraving; Unidentified
  - Engraving of [Lancaster], ca 1820; 1 engraving; Unidentified
    4 3/4" x 7 1/4"
  - Engraving of the High Street Market in 1800, ca 1820; 1 engraving; Unidentified
    4" x 6"
  - Engraving of Simon Snyder, ca 1820; 1 engraving; Pinx. W. Wooley, engraver, from painting by Tibout
    10" x 7"
  - Engraving of Burke, ca 1830; 1 engraving; Wagstaff, Charles Edward, 1808-1850, engraver, from portrait by Joshua Reynolds
  - Engraving of Peter Pindar, ca 1830; 1 engraving; Halpin, engraver, from original painting
    7" x 5"
  - Engraving of Richard Brinsley Sheridan, ca 1830; 1 engraving; Woolnoth, Thomas, b. 1785, engraver
    7' x 4 1/2"
  - Engraving of John Adams, ca 1830; 1 engraving; Longacre, James Barton, 1794-1869, engraver, from a painting by B. Otis after the portrait by G. Stuart
    8 1/4" x 6 1/4"